Violet Lowens D.C. Arts and Culture Collection 090
People's Archive, MLK Library
Violet Lowens D.C. Arts and Culture Collection
1942-1983
People's Archive, MLK Library
Lowens, Violet
090
1 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Biographical / Historical
Although there is no biographical information on Violet Lowens, the materials in this collection suggest that she was a patron of the arts in Washington, D.C. It also appears that Lowens may have worked for the Library of the Arts at DC Public Library in the 1970s.
Custodial History
Violet Lowens donated these materials to the Library in October 1997.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of memorabilia, programs, invitations, correspondence, clippings, and newsletters from a variety of arts and culture institutions in Washington, D.C., including items related to theatre, musicals, concerts, exhibits, speeches, and dance performances.
Performing Arts; Theatre; Music; Exhibitions; Dance; Arts
- Series 1
  - American Bach Foundation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arena Stage - Living Stage, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Association for Recorded Sound Collections, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bach, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven Society of Washington DC, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Calligraphers Guild, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Choral Arts Society of Washington, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paul Hill Chorale, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - City Dance, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Contemporary Music Forum, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Corcoran, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - DC Department of Recreation and Washington Civic Opera Association, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Donor List, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Encore! Dinner Theatre, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ephemera, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Folger Consort, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Folger Theatre Group, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Foundry Opera Group, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Friends of Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Library, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Paul T. Goodnight, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Greg Reynolds Dance Quintet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Immaculate Conception Dance Co., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Inter-American Music Festival, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kennedy Center, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kindler Foundation, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Library for the Arts - DC Public Library, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress - Calendar of Events, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Library of Congress - Invitations, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Library of Congress - Musical Concerts, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Library of Congress - Musical Concerts, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Library of Congress - Pamphlets, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Library of Congress - Press Releases, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Market 5 Gallery, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Museum of African Art, 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mutual Manhattan Variety Cavalcade, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - National Symphony Orchestra, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - National Theatre, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - New Back Alley Theatre - "Compulsion", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - New Playwright's Theatre, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Opera Libretti, 1967-1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Opera - Southwest, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Oratorio Society of Washington, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Performing Arts Library, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Phillips Collection, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Smithsonian Institution - Associate, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Erika Thimey, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Warner Theatre, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Washington Opera Guild, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Washington Performing Arts Society, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Wolf Trap, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)